前情提要
当我达到自己的目的后
When I've achieved what I set out to achieve
我会告诉你枪藏在哪
I'll let you know where to find the guns.
我该怎么做
So what shall I do?
接近他  查出枪藏在哪里
Get close to him. Find out where those guns are hidden.
想要罢工的人  举起手来
Raise a hand if you want to strike!
我名单上的第一个人就是弗莱迪·索恩
Freddie Thorne is at the very top of my list.
划掉他吧  我把他纳入我们的交易条件
Well, cross him off. I'll make him part of our deal.
让他们去死吧
To hell with them.
他们越是想阻碍我们  我就会越疯狂
The more they try to stop us, the madder I'll be.
这年头  家里有个共产主义分子会影响生意
Times like these, a communist in the family is bad for business.
你必须离开这里
You have to leave the city.
你也在和他们交战  对吧  肯波先生
You are also at war with the Lees, Mr Kimber, am I right?
我们合力可以打垮他们  但分而作战  就不一定了
Together we can beat them. Divided, maybe not.
天啊  他越长越大了
God, he's getting big now.
-我长肥了  你还依然爱我吗  -不会
- Do you still love me even though I am fat? - No.
一点不爱吗
Not at all?
你娶了我  你别想甩掉我了
You married me, now you're stuck with me.
伦敦怎么样
So, how was London?
革命之火处处燃起
It's crackling with revolution.
白杨码头的人正在罢工
The Poplar docks are on strike.
我们的朋友们给了我们想要的东西吗
Did our friends give us what we asked for?
-多少  -200英镑
- How much? - 200 pounds.
你跟谁见面了
Who did you meet?
俄国大使馆的一个随员
An attache from the Russian embassy.
在中餐厅见的面
In a Chinese restaurant.
我们的革命是国际化的
Our revolution is international.
而且它日益发展壮大
And it grows by the day.
浴   血
黑   帮
第一季   『人人影视英剧社倾情奉献』   第四集
贾玛尔  贾玛尔  你看见什么了
Jeremiah, Jeremiah... What do you see?
你妹妹和弗莱迪今早回来了
Your sister and Freddie got back this morning.
我试图跟踪他们
I tried following them...
但弗莱迪太擅长潜藏躲避了
but Freddie's so good at getting away.
他就像鱼一样狡猾
He's like a fish.
好吧  你要继续捕鱼  明白吗
Right, well, keep fishing, eh?
我们要等到那些小子们就位再行动
最后下注了  别把房租都赌上了  查理
Last bets now! Don't spend your rent money, Charlie!
开始发令了  先生们
That's your starters, gentlemen.
不能再下注了
No more bets.
-我准时赶到了  -已经结束了
- I was here on time. - Finished.
我搞到内部消息了  我必须下注
I've had a tip-off, I need this bet.
-比赛已经开始了  -求你了
- The race has started. - Please.
不行
No!
行吧
Fine.
把他赶出去
Get rid of him.
我们说了不行  滚出去
We said, "No", now get out!
好吧  行  我走  我走
All right. All right, I'm off. I'm off.
-再见  兄弟  -明天见
- Night, lads. - See you tomorrow.
今天不错
It's a good day.
约翰去哪儿了
Where's John?
约翰去加里森酒吧了
John is in the Garrison.
他说他想开个会讨论家事
He says he wants a meeting about a family matter.
等他说完了
After he's said his piece
他就会回来顶替斯卡德伯特的
he'll come back and take his place with Scudboat.
斯卡德伯特  约翰十分钟后就会回来
Scudboat? John will be here in ten minutes.
好的
All right.
5分钟
Five.
等等
Wait.
好孩子
Good boy.
约翰
John?
把枪放下  把枪放下
Put that down! Put that down!
这是为报切尔滕纳姆之仇
This is for Cheltenham.
我们只是拿回原本就属于我们的东西
We're just taking back what's ours.
这里有钱  到处搜一遍
There's money here. Search everywhere.
好了  约翰  现在只有一个...不
All right, John. There's only one right... No.
现在只有一个人守着赌马房
There's only one man guarding the house.
你遇到什么麻烦事了
What's troubling you?
波莉  你也知道玛莎死后我家里的情况
Polly, you know what it's been like since Martha died.
好人不长命
God takes the best first.
事实上  我的孩子们整天都在我身边晃悠
The truth is, my kids have been running bloody rings around me.
赤着脚  整天牵着狗乱跑
Running barefoot with the dogs until all hours.
波莉  给他十先令  买些新鞋
Pol, give him ten bob, some new shoes.
是想要这些吗  约翰
Is that it, John?
汤米  你最好不要插嘴这事
Tommy, we'd be better doing this without you.
你到底想说什么
Now, what's your point?
孩子们需要的是一个母亲
What the kids need is a mother.
所以我要再婚了
So, that's why I'm getting married.
那个可怜的姑娘知道你要娶她吗
Does this poor girl know you're going to marry her
还是你打算突然地要求和她结婚
or are you going to spring it on her all of a sudden?
我已经求过婚了  她也答应了
I've already proposed and she said "Yes".
我看就像一个炸药筒要落地爆炸了
I think there's a shell about to land and go bang.
她叫  莉兹·斯塔克
It's, er... It's Lizzie Stark.
约翰  莉兹·斯塔克是个强大的女人
John, Lizzie Stark's a strong woman
我敢说她一定把客人们都"服务"得很好
and I am sure she provides a fine service for her customers.
我不想听那个词
I WON'T hear the word.
明白吗  不要用那个词
Understand? Do not use that word.
哪个词啊  约翰
What word is that, John?
你心里清楚是哪个词
You know what word that is.
大家都他妈知道
Everybody bloody knows...
那大家都可以去死了
Everybody can go to hell...
"婊子"  是这个词吗  还是"妓女"
"Whore"? That word? Or "Prostitute"?
那个词如何
How about that one?
好吧  我要让大家知道
Right, I want it known...
如果谁再敢叫她"婊子"
if anyone calls her a "Whore" Again,
我就把左轮手枪的枪管伸进他们的喉咙
I will push the barrel of my revolver down their throats
把从他们口中说出的话再打回去
and blow the word back down into their hearts.
男人和男人的鸡巴总引我发笑
Men and their cocks never cease to amaze me.
约翰  莉兹·斯塔克都没站着干过活
John, Lizzie Stark never did a day's work vertical.
她改了  明白吗  人是会改变的
She's changed. All right. People change.
就跟  宗  宗教信仰一样
Like wi-wi-with religion.
莉兹也有宗教信仰是吗
Oh, Lizzie Stark has got religion, eh?
不  不  她没有宗教信仰  但
No, no, she doesn't have religion. But...
她爱我
Well, she loves me.
听着  汤米  没有你的祝福  我是不会娶她的
Now, listen, Tommy. I won't do it without your blessing.
但在世上所有人当中
But of all the people in the world...
我希望你把这视作  勇敢的行为
I want you to see it...as brave.
是真够勇敢的
It's brave all right.
勇敢的意思是开创无人做过的伟业
"Brave" is going where no man has gone before.
至于莉兹·斯塔克  约翰
With Lizzy Stark, John,
那真的算不上什么勇敢
that is really not what you'll be doing.
听着  汤米  欢迎她加入我们的家庭
Listen, Tommy. Welcome her to the family.
她此前人生坎坷受尽欺凌
As someone who's had a hard life.
好吗  因为  我需要有个人陪在我身边
All right? Because, I need someone.
孩子们需要有个人来陪伴他们
All right, the kids need someone.
汤米  我们被洗劫了
Tommy! We've been done over!
什么
What?
老天啊
Jesus Christ.
到底他妈的发生什么事了
What the bloody hell happened here?
李氏家族的人  全来了
The Lees. All of them.
表亲  侄子  私生子都来了
Cousins, nephews, even the bastards.
他们拿走了一切可以拿走的东西
They've taken anything they can lay their hands on.
4个现金钱箱
Four cash boxes.
他们丢下了这些
They left these....
钢丝钳  他们为什么要留下钢丝钳
Wire cutters. Why would they leave wire cutters?
大家都别动
Nobody move.
我觉得我们的朋友们在玩游戏
I think our friends are playing the game.
-什么游戏  -波莉阿姨  别碰任何东西
- What game? - Aunt Pol. Don't touch anything.
伊拉兹马斯·李曾去过法国
Erasmus Lee was in France.
该死
Shit.
当我们撤退  把土地让给德军时
When we gave up ground to the Germans...
我们会留下陷阱  用钢丝来触发
We'd leave behind booby traps, set up with wires.
我们会同时留下钢丝钳  算是开个玩笑
And we'd leave wire cutters as part of the joke.
-这里某个地方有个手榴弹  -老天啊
- Somewhere in here there's a hand grenade... - Holy Jesus.
用钢丝连接着
Attached to a wire.
不要移动椅子  或者关门
Don't move any chairs or open any doors.
-淡定点  小约翰  淡定  -不
- Go easy, John boy. Easy. - No.
兄弟们  不  不在这里
Boys, no. It's not in here.
如果是在这里  应该已经爆炸了
If it was in here, it would have blown by now.
伊拉兹马斯送来的那枚子弹上写的是我的名字
It was my name on that bullet Erasmus sent.
他是会设陷阱
He's set a trap all right.
但他只想搞死我一个人
But he's set it up just for me.
芬恩
Finn?
芬恩  待在那儿别动
Finn, stay exactly where you are.
我在假扮你呢
I was pretending I was you.
你是开哪扇门上车的  芬恩
Which door did you open to come in, Finn?
我没开门  我爬进来的
I didn't. I climbed in.
我要你按照爬进去的方式原路爬出来  明白吗
I want you to climb out exactly the same way you climbed in, OK?
不  不  芬恩
No, no... Finn!
让开
Clear!
发生什么事了
What happened?
-你没事吧  -没事  差点炸死我们了
- Are you all right? - Yeah, yeah. It could have killed us.
所以说你永远不该假扮我
That's why you should never pretend to be me.
明白吗  明白吗
Ok? Ok?
我帮你争取了十分钟和她见面的时间
I got you ten minutes with her.
你至少该说声谢谢吧
You can at least say thank you.
现在要见教皇都比见她容易
It's easier to get to see the Pope these days.
把手放在圣经上
Put your hand on the Bible.
我不信教
I don't believe.
反正  我到这儿来也不是为了说谎
Anyway, I didn't come here to lie.
争战让我们都有死伤
This war is cutting us all up.
一个小男孩差点被炸死
一个孩子
你们都是孩子
You're all children.
我觉得该到此为止了
I say enough.
你的孩子们试图杀死我  但没有成功
Your boys tried to kill me - it didn't work.
我想提出一个解决办法
我以为他是你的同盟呢
我打算背叛他
难怪你不敢碰圣经
No wonder you won't touch a Bible.
-我有雄心抱负  -你想玩两面派
- I have ambitions. - You want to play a switch.
我需要你那些手下
I need your boys.
去干什么
For what?
肯波不是背后动脑筋的人
Kimber's not the brains.
实际掌管赛马场的是另外一个人
There's a gadze who runs the races.
我在拉拢聪明人  但我也需要四肢发达的人
I'm collecting smart people. But I need strong men too.
你的那些手下们该清楚这一点
Now your boys should know this,
我们现在每三场比赛就可以操控一次由谁赢
we now get the winner in one of every three races
在比赛开始前就决定好了
before the race even starts.
不需要收什么粉笔费或博彩
No need for chalkers or rafflers.
我说的是确定的事
I'm talking certainties.
你跑来吹嘘说你要背叛某人  把他搞下台
You come in here boasting you're going to do someone down
然后又用同样的语气请我信任你
and in the same breath you ask me to trust you.
就我母亲这一边来说  我们是近亲
On my mother's side, we are kin.
我们来谈谈家族生意吧
艾达  能帮我搓搓背吗
Ada, can you do my back?
艾达
Ada?
我知道信封里装的是什么
I know what was in the envelope.
我看过了  是钱
I looked. Money.
你说我们在伦敦见的人是法国人
And that bloke we met in London who you said was a Frenchman.
其实是俄国人  我不傻  弗莱迪
He was Russian. I'm not an idiot, Freddie.
为什么风险都由你来承担
How is it you take all the risks
而钱都归斯坦利·查普曼
and Stanly Chapman gets the money?
那钱是为了共产主义大业
It's money for the cause.
你个瞎子看不清状况
You're blind.
如果跟你的哥哥们有关  那我肯定要瞎
I would be if your brothers had anything to do with it.
这事跟他们无关  只跟你有关
This isn't about them. This is about you.
和我  还有这个
And me. And...this.
你是个梦想家  弗莱迪
You're a dreamer, Freddie.
你广施钱财而我们却在这里穷困潦倒
You give money away while we rot in here...
你把革命一直挂在嘴上
and you talk about revolution.
我需要知道
I need to know.
你效忠于谁  弗莱迪
Who are you loyal to, Freddie?
我问了  "你效忠于谁"
I said, "Who are you loyal to?"
你跟这事有什么关系吗
Did you have something to do with this?
我问一位熟人要的地址
I asked an acquaintance for an address.
她说给我的唯一条件就是不要提到她的名字
She said she would only give it to me anonymously.
她害怕被别人报复
She was afraid of the consequences.
这是谁的地址
Whose address is it?
汤米  我觉得有个策略可行
Tommy, I'd like to suggest a strategy.
你传话说你有个地址要给我
Your message said you have an address for me.
匿名密报
Anonymous tip off.
斯坦利·查普曼的住址
The address of Stanly Chapman.
你保证过会给我找到弗莱迪·索恩
You promised me Freddie Thorne.
用这个来代替弗莱迪·索恩
This is instead of Freddie Thorne.
-没门  -督察
- No deal. - Inspector,
斯坦利·查普曼可是比弗莱迪·索恩更重要的人物
Stanly Chapman is a bigger fish than Freddie Thorne.
他现在拿着200英镑的现金
He is currently holding 200 pounds in cash.
是俄国政府资助给共产党的
Given to the Communist party by the Russian Government.
没错
That's right,
查普曼露出了狐狸尾巴
Chapman has snow on his boots
而你只要趁机一网打尽就好
and all you'll need is a shovel.
如果他招供  你就有证据了
If he talks, you'll have proof.
你甚至可能得到国王奖章
You might even get that medal.
现在
Now...
在我给你地址之前
before I give you the address...
我需要你保证
I want your word...
你会让弗莱迪·索恩和我妹妹
that you will let Freddie Thorne and my sister
离开这座城市
leave the city.
很好  我向你保证
Very well. You have my word.
我觉得我们的休战协议对我们两人来说
I'd say our little truce is proving productive
都是件好事  督察
for both of us, Inspector.
我能获得情报
I get the information...
和保护  而你
and protection and you...
能抓到布尔什维克分子
you get Bolsheviks.
但现在有件更紧迫的事
But on a more pressing matter...
我看丘吉尔已逐渐失去耐心了
I'm afraid that Mr. Churchill is becoming impatient.
而且我担心
And I fear that...
如果你不赶快把那批偷走的武器还回来
if you don't give back those stolen weapons soon...
我会遭到取代
I will be replaced.
那样的话我就完蛋了  那是肯定的
That would be the finish of me, that's for sure.
我跟肯波的交易结束时
When my business with Kimber is done
我会归还那批枪的  之前说好的
the guns will be returned. That was the deal.
我现在完全被你操控着
Then I am in your hands. Completely.
你握着全部的王牌
You hold all the cards.
但我希望不要赶在你决定
But I hope to God that my dismissal doesn't come
归还那批枪之前被解雇
before your decision to hand back those guns.
我这么说是为你好  因为
I say this for your sake, because...
如果我被解雇了  而且那是你的错
if I were to be fired and it were your fault...
我会做出连恶魔都自惭形愧的事
I would do things that would shame the devil.
我生起气来你就要小心了
My fury is a thing to behold.
比如说  在我在任的最后一天
On my last day in power, for example,
我会让你和你那些垃圾弟兄们
I would see to it that you and your scum brothers
脑袋被棒子和铁铲拍得稀巴烂
have your heads stoved in with mallets and spades.
包括你的妹妹
And your sister too.
她怀的孩子对我来说一点都不重要
That baby inside her would be of no consequence to me.
唯一会幸免于难的
The only one to be spared...
就是你的小弟弟芬恩
would be your little brother Finn.
他会被作为少年犯起诉
He would however be lifted as a juvenile
然后被扔进成人监狱里
and dumped into that part of the adult prison...
像他那样的男孩  在那里最受欢迎了
where men have most appetite for boys like him.
那可真是黑暗无边的日子了  谢尔比先生
That would be a dark day indeed, Mr. Shelby.
如果在你做决定前  我就被解雇了
If my dismissal comes before your decision.
你明白吗
Do you understand?
再提醒你一下
And know this...
时间不等人
the clock is ticking.
斯坦利  我们是警察  斯坦利  过来
Stanly, it's the police. Stanly, get here!
-你被逮捕了  伙计  -你们这帮混蛋
- You're under arrest, mate! - You bastards!
看看我们找到了什么
Look what we found.
看来斯坦利·查普曼的狐狸尾巴
It seems Stanly Chapman really
确实已经漏出来了
does have snow on his boots.
查普曼先生
Mr. Chapman...
你死定了
you're fucked.
他还是不说那钱是从哪来的
He still refuses to say where it came from.
我相信  好好说服他一番的话
I'm sure, with a little persuasion,
他会和盘托出的
he'll tell us everything he knows.
包括弗莱迪·索恩的行踪
Including the whereabouts of Freddie Thorne.
-长官  -你的想法都写在脸上了
- Sir? - Your face is a picture.
我以为你跟他谈好交易了
I thought you had done a deal.
原来你是这么想的
Oh, is that is what you thought.
你保证过了啊
Well, you gave your word.
我保证过
My word?
在现在这个愚蠢的年代  人们还在乎这种事呢
Do people still talk about such things this idiotic century?
我向谁保证过
My word to who?
向一个剃刀党成员吗
To a Peaky Blinder?
现在  去好好审讯查普曼先生
Now, go and interrogate Mr. Chapman
直到他告诉我们在哪儿
until he tells us where
能找到弗莱迪·索恩和他的妻子
we can find Freddie Thorne and his wife.
找到钱的来源是次要的
The source of the money is of secondary importance.
你认为我对谢尔比采取行动是出于私人恩怨吗
You think my campaign against Shelby has become personal?
没错
Correct.
完全正确  在伦敦他们会这么说
"Spot-on", as they say in London society.
现在去审讯查普曼先生
Now, go and interrogate Mr. Chapman
记得下手不要太温柔
and do not make the mistake of being too gentle.
明白  长官
Right, sir.
今天是她的诞辰
Today's her birthday.
我就知道你不会不来的
I know you never miss it.
幸好你不是警察
Then I'm lucky you're not a copper.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我是来警告你的
I came to warn you.
他们已经抓住了斯坦利·查普曼
They've lifted Stanly Chapman.
你怎么知道的  警方并未透漏任何信息
How do you know? Police don't spill that information.
我知道是因为是我和汤米告的密
I know cos it was me and Tommy who tipped them off.
汤米跟他做了个交易
Tommy did a deal.
为了让你和艾达安全离开
In return for safe passage for you and Ada
他告诉警方关于斯坦利和钱的事
he's given them Stanly and the money.
钱  什么钱
Money? What money?
-谁告诉你钱的事的  -你觉得是谁
- Who told you about the money? - Who do you think?
没错  是艾达的主意  她为了能搬出那个
Yeah, it was Ada's idea. That's how desperate she is
像老鼠洞一样的家已经不择手段了
to get out of that rat-hole you're keeping her in.
她不介意你知道是她干的
She doesn't mind if you knew
但她希望你知道真相时她不在场
she just didn't want to be here when you found out.
有时女人不得不站出来  就像战争期间
Sometimes the women have to take over. Like in the war.
你他妈以为自己是什么人
Who the hell do you think you are,
你个该死的谢尔比
you fucking Shelbys.
别站在你妈的坟墓上骂脏话
Don't swear over your mother's grave.
你们玩弄手段  认为地球就该绕着你们转
You play your tune, you expect the whole world to dance to it.
没时间让你在这浪费了  弗莱迪
You don't have time for this, Freddie.
你为了我做了交易
You did a deal for me?
别自作多情  是为了艾达
Don't flatter yourself. For Ada.
你以为那个警察会信守诺言
And you think this copper will keep his word.
如果他守了  你们就安全了
If he does, you're safe.
如果他没有  查普曼会供出你
If he doesn't, Chapman will give you up,
你们还是要离开这里  结果都一样
you'll still have to leave town. Same result.
-很聪明啊  -那就快走
- So neat. - So leave.
除了你搞错了一件事
Except there's one thing that you got wrong.
斯坦利不会供出我的住址
Stanly won't be able to give up my address
因为他根本就不知情
because he doesn't know it.
组织内就是这么操作的
That's how it works.
我们都不知道对方的住址
None of us know each other's addresses.
看来你是浪费时间了
So, you've wasted your fucking time.
他们会一直拷打他
They'll keep beating him and
想要问出他根本不知道的情报
beating him for information he doesn't have.
你做的一切就是将一个好人判了死刑
All you've done is sign the death warrant of a good man.
那你不会走了
So, you won't leave.
不  我他妈才不会走
No! I won't fucking leave!
要我离开伯明翰
If you want me out of Birmingham
只有等我死了
it'll have to be in a wooden box.
如果你敢对艾达动手
You lay a hand on our Ada,
我会亲手送你进坟墓
I'll put you in a wooden box myself.
你养了个顽固不化的儿子  艾琳
You raised a stubborn one there, Irene.
你吩咐过我要继续审讯  我想先暂缓一下
You told me to carry on. I wanted to stop.
他好像癫痫发作了
He had some kind of seizure.
你杀了他吗
So, you killed him?
他告诉你住址了吗
Did he give you an address?
你到底怎么回事
What's the matter with you?
他不过是从楼梯上摔下来了
He fell down some stairs.
这里可不是贝尔法斯特
This is not bloody Belfast!
现在还不是
Not yet,
但如果像他这种人得逞了  很快就一样了
but if men like him get their way, it soon will be.
再把他从楼梯上扔下去
So, find some stairs, throw him down,
然后去找验尸官
and call the coroner.
去找格雷森
Use Grayson.
如果他多嘴问起什么的话
If he has any awkward questions
问问他和萨尔特利那个情妇之间的风流事
ask about the welfare of his mistress in Saltley.
那就能让他闭嘴了
That'll shut him up.
我以前也住在这种破地方
To think I used to live in a shit-hole like this.
到处都是老鼠
Bloody animals.
但谢尔比确实为我们贡献不小
But the Shelbys really are doing an excellent job for us.
在八场赛马比赛里  我们没损失一分
We haven't lost a single penny to rafflers or chalkers
粉笔费和博彩费
in eight race meetings.
赌注经纪人很开心
The bookies are purring.
我们扔了块骨头给看门狗
So, we throw the dog a bone.
确实如此
I think so.
肯波先生  罗伯茨先生  下来看看吧
Mr. Kimber. Mr Roberts. Come and have a look around.
您先请
After you.
得了吧  弗雷德
Come on, Fred.
你吃中饭的钱就能养活半个伯明翰了
You can feed half of Birmingham with what you have had for lunch.
回去工作
Get back to work.
我们听说李氏家族的人把你的地方洗劫了
We heard the Lees had turned you over.
你不该听信谣言  肯波先生  这边走
You shouldn't listen to gossip, Mr Kimber. This way.
生意不错
Business is good.
特别是你现在知道哪匹马会赢
Especially since now you know which horse is going to win
就能提前设好赔率
before you set the odds.
很感谢你们提供的信息
Your information is very much appreciated.
好了  他们在哪
Right, well, where are they?
约翰  拉夫洛克  斯卡德伯特  都过来
John, Lovelock, Scudboat, in here.
这是我的团队
This is my team.
他们愿意随时为你效劳  肯波先生
They will take up their pitch at your convenience, Mr. Kimber.
约翰是记账册的  斯卡德伯特是负责赌注的
John is the book. Scudboat is the bag man.
当然  我们自己带保镖
And, of course, we bring our own protection.
去瓦里克  下周六
Warwick, next Saturday.
不许接近啤酒棚五十码以内
At least fifty yards from the beer tent.
先生们
Gentlemen...
还有女士
and lady.
我拿的是合法赌马的许可证
I have in my hand a legal betting licence.
由管理委员会下发的
Issued by the board of control.
谢尔比家族拿到了他们第一张
The Shelby family has its first
合法赌马许可证
legal racetrack pitch.
我们是生意人了  波莉
We're a business, Pol.
-恭喜  -给你看
- Congratulations. - There you go.
恭喜
Congratulations.
三十  四十  五十
30, 40, 50...
香烟有股怪味  亚瑟
These cigarettes have a strange smell, Arthur.
闻起来像臭水沟  你看
They smell like rotting water. And look.
有些被老鼠啃了
Rats have gotten some of them.
这是偷的  对吗
They're stolen, are they not?
别多问
Don't ask.
它们藏在船上  所以有怪味
They smell because you keep them on a boat.
问这么多干嘛
What do you care? Now,
过来帮我看有没有算错  拜托
can you come and check my adding up, please?
你应该重新整顿一下这里
You know, you should make a new start with this place.
搞得像样点  那些香烟没法卖
Do it properly. These cigarettes are not fit to sell.
加利波利的味道
Smells like Gallipoli.
你应该找个新地方存货
You should find a new place to store them.
必须远离警察
It has to be far away from coppers.
-那老鼠呢  -码头都有老鼠  格蕾丝
- But not rats? - All the wharves have rats, Grace.
-为什么不放在干燥的仓库  -汤米下过命令
- What's wrong with a dry warehouse? - Tommy's orders.
什么命令
What orders?
违禁品永远要放在码头旁的燃油船上
Always keep contraband near to petrol boat moorings.
船也会被搜查的
Don't boats get searched?
我们停在两河交汇处
We moor them at junctions...
有两条逃路
so there's more than one way out.
一英里内没有船闸门  所以机动性强
No locks within a mile so we can move that stuff fast.
你兄弟不守法律  却有自己的规矩
Your brother doesn't obey the law, but he has rules.
你兄弟真是谨慎啊
A precise man, your brother.
-我算的对吗  -现在对了
- Is my adding up right? - It is now.
一
One.
二
Two.
三...和四
Three...and four.
我们一个个搜
And we'll search them one by one.
祈求上帝  但愿我要找的东西在这里
Please, Lord, let that which I seek be found here.
没有子弹  长官  只有香烟和威士忌
Not so much as a bullet, sir. Just more cigarettes and whisky.
亚瑟说你问他
Arthur tells me you've been asking questions...
我们生意的事
..about how we run our business.
我们如何得到酒  在哪里储存
And how we get our booze and where we keep it.
我只是想帮忙
I am just trying to help.
我们走走
Let's you and me go for a walk.
-去哪  -来吧
- Where to? - Come on.
为什么来这里
Why here?
你是个虔诚的天主教徒  对吗
You're a good Catholic girl, aren't you?
对
Yes.
那你就知道人们会来这里坦白忏悔
Well, then you know it's here people come to confess.
你先请
After you.
开始吧  格蕾丝
Well, here it is, Grace.
我坦白
I confess.
我需要一个人
I need someone.
肯波有个叫罗伯茨的顾问
Kimber has an adviser by the name of Roberts.
他口才好
He talks well.
替肯波记账
Keeps the accounts.
负责他们的合法生意
Runs the legal side of the business.
你也想找个顾问
And you need a Roberts.
亚瑟说你点子多
Arthur tells me you have ideas.
我不是会计  也不是律师
I'm not an accountant. Nor a lawyer.
没错
No.
但你有我想要的东西
No, but you have something I need.
气质
Class.
重要会议时我需要仪表端庄的人
I need someone who looks right at the big meetings.
艾普森赛马会  阿斯科特赛马会
Epsom, Ascot...
-这是面试吗  -亚瑟说你很会算账
- Is a job interview? - Arthur says you're good with numbers.
那是相对而言  因为他太烂了
Well, that's relative. He is quite poor.
-你能整清账目  -因为太乱了
- You keep the books in order. - They were chaotic.
但你是个骗子
But you're a liar.
天主教徒进教堂时
No Catholic girl would enter a church
都会在胸前划十字
and forget to make the sign of the cross.
你真是洞察秋毫
You are very perceptive.
你先是谎报曾经工作过的酒吧
First, you lied about that pub you used worked in.
现在我又发现你是个新教徒
Now I find out you're a Protestant.
你在乎吗
Do you care?
不
No.
我撒谎是为了融入这里
I lied to fit in.
你倒酒时毫无经验
You pull a pint like someone who's thinking about it.
-这不是面试  这是审问  -坐下
- This is not an interview, it is an interrogation. - Sit down.
听着  格蕾丝
Look, Grace...
你来到了这个不属于你的地方
You washed up in a place you don't belong
我不管你是出于什么原因
for whatever reason.
-我很幸运  -或许我也是
- My good fortune. - And perhaps mine.
-我做的大部分事都非法  -我不是瞎子
- You know that most of what I do is illegal. - I'm not blind.
但你还是愿意为我工作
And yet, you'd still be willing to work for me?
你这是给我提供工作吗
Are you offering me the job?
我接受
Then I accept.
还有件事你应该知道
There's something else you should know.
我雇用你还有一个重要原因
A very important detail about my reasons for employing you.
你令我失望
You disappoint me.
你会辞职吗
Do you resign?
不
No.
我对这工作的兴趣反而更大了
My appetite for the work has only increased.
明天我带你熟悉工作
Tomorrow I'll show you around.
莉兹  你好  莉兹
Lizzie. Hello, Lizzie.
那袋子看起来很沉  上车吧
That bag looks heavy, jump in.
孩子们的茶
Kids' teas.
你喜欢孩子吗
You like kids?
-是的  -很好  约翰有4个孩子
- Yeah. - Good, cos John's got four of them.
放心吧  我不会劝你放弃
It's all right. I'm not going to try to talk you out of it.
我只是想谈谈
I just want to talk.
你不反对我们
You're not against us?
约翰能自己做主
John is his own man.
你也是
And you are your own woman.
莉兹
Now, Lizzie...
从法国回来后
since I came back from France,
我去找过你好几次
I've come to you on many occasions.
-汤米  你没告诉他吧  -没  我没有
- Tommy, you didn't tell him? - No, I didn't tell him.
正如你也没告诉他一样
Just like you didn't tell him.
你为什么不告诉他  莉兹
Now, why didn't you tell him, Lizzie?
你为什么不告诉他
Why didn't you tell him
过去两年一直在接待他的哥哥
that you'd been serving his brother for the past two years?
因为往事已埋葬在过去
Because the past is the past.
我不想失去他  他是个好男人
I don't want to lose him. He's a good man.
我就希望你这么回答
That was the answer I was hoping you'd give -
"往事已埋葬在过去"
the past is the past.
约翰说你变了  我相信他
You see our John says you've changed. And I believe him.
这很好  改变是好事
And that's good. Change is good.
现在时代不一样了
These are new times I'm told.
所以我希望你们幸福美满
So I wish you both every happiness.
这算是我给你的结婚礼物
And I want you to see that as my wedding gift to you.
以及对曾经欢愉的最后回味
And our farewell to pleasures gone by.
你是说
You mean...
最后回味一次
..one last time?
最后一次  你和我
One last time. You and me.
整整八英镑呢
It's eight bloody pounds.
我们去哪做
So, where shall we go?
汤米  去我的住处吗
Tommy, shall we go to my lodging?
看来往事依旧啊
So, the past is not the past.
钱你留下  莉兹  下车吧
You can keep the money, Lizzie. Just get out of the car.
-汤米  求你了  -下车
- Tommy, please... - Get out of the car.
我真的爱他  汤米
I love him, Tommy. Really.
真的
Really.
约翰将自己下决定
John will make his own decision.
但我会告诉他事实
But he will have the facts.
你弟弟比你够爷们儿十倍
Your brother is ten times the man you are!
这点我毫不怀疑
Of that I have no doubt.
他显然不蠢
He is obviously not stupid.
我们只找到了被偷的烟草和威士忌
All we found was stolen tobacco and whisky.
你放回原地了吧
Which you left in place.
当然
Of course.
我永远不会危及你
I would never endanger you.
你干得很好  格蕾丝
You are doing well, Grace.
我在套亚瑟的话  他比较容易打通
I've been working on Arthur, he's easier.
-比汤玛斯容易  -是的
- Than Thomas. - Yes.
他没那么精明
Less intelligent.
对
Yes.
你会用"精明"来形容汤玛斯吗
Is that a word you would use about Thomas?
那是你说的
It's your word.
他晋升了我
He has promoted me.
他想让我当他的会计和秘书
He wants me to be his book-keeper and secretary.
一帮暴徒还要秘书
A cut-throat gangster with a secretary.
这帮流氓矫情得动人心魄
The pretensions of these hoodlums are quite breathtaking!
不是吗
Are they not?
是的  很动人
Yes. Quite breathtaking.
显然他很中意你
He has obviously fallen quite heavily for you.
我以为你会高兴
I thought you would be pleased.
我只是希望你记得他是什么样的人
I just hope you remember who you are dealing with here.
一个剁耳切舌的人
A man who cuts off ears and cuts out tongues.
我知道他是什么样的人  长官
I know what he is, sir.
卧底最难的一点就是
The difficulty with undercover work,
时刻谨记自己是谁  格蕾丝
Grace, is to remember what you are.
我带来好消息  你却这样回报
I come here with good news and I get this.
格蕾丝
Grace!
汤米  帮我个忙
Tommy. I need a favour.
我想借一下车
I want to borrow the car.
我要带莉兹和孩子们去乡下转转
I want to take Lizzie for a ride in the country with the kids.
我们要庆祝拿到执照
We're going to celebrate getting the licence.
没问题  约翰
Not a problem, John.
我需要钥匙
I'll need the keys.
约翰  你是我弟弟
Look, John, you're my brother...
有件事我必须告诉你
There's something I have to tell you.
昨天在车前座
Yesterday on the front seat of that car,
我向莉兹花钱买春
I offered Lizzie some money.
约翰  她同意了
And, John, she said "Yes".
那是事实
Now, that's a fact.
想怎么办你自己定
You do with it what want.
拿上钥匙
Take the keys.
带莉兹去乡下
Take Lizzie to the country.
如果你愿意  可以跟她结婚
Marry her if you want.
但你必须知道
But you have to know...
她同意了
..she said "Yes".
再拿个杯子
Get another glass.
你会祝酒吗
Can you make a toast?
我是爱尔兰人  祝酒最拿手
I'm Irish, I can make a million toasts.
愿你在被魔鬼带走之前
May you be in heaven a full half hour
先在天堂快活半个小时
before the devil knows you're dead.
我们在庆祝什么
What are we celebrating?
雇佣合同
Contract of employment.
会计  谢尔比兄弟有限公司
Book-keeper. Shelby Brothers Limited.
我不喜欢"有限"这个词
I don't like that word, "Limited".
要想被尊重  你必须加上"有限"
To be respectable, you have to be "Limited".
那也是我担心的
That's what worries me.
我装电话了
I had the phone put in.
就在后面
It's in the back.
如果谁也有电话  我们就可以打给他了
If we knew someone else who had a phone, we could call them.
既然我们在庆祝
And since we are celebrating...
这是我从拉克姆百货公司订的酒
..I had this delivered from Rackham's Department Store.
你能打开吗
Will you open it?
不
No.
留到特殊场合再喝
Save it for a special occasion.
对了  你为公司做的第一件事
Right, your first job for the company.
就是把这个送给我妹妹
I want you to get that to my sister.
我没见到她啊
I don't see her?
没人见到过  她在躲着我
No-one does. She is hiding from me.
我听说在女士专浴日  她会去蒙塔古街的澡堂
I am told she goes to a bathhouse on Montague Street on woman-only days.
她会伪装  所以我必须在里面有人
She goes in disguise, so I need to get someone inside.
我要送什么
What am I delivering?
一场家族聚会的邀请函  我要她到场
It's an invitation to a family occasion. I want her there.
告诉她当天休战
So, tell her there will be a truce.
我要送的是陷阱的诱饵吗
Am I delivering bait for a trap?
如果你仔细看这份合同
If you check that contract
就会发现上面说了不要问太多问题
I think you'll find it doesn't say anything about asking questions.
直接把邀请函给她就行
Just give her the invitation.
把那瓶酒放进柜子里  我叫你拿再拿出来
And put that in the cupboard until I say.
-搞什么啊  约翰  -我点不着烟枪
- What the hell, John? - I couldn't get it lit.
我连那个都做不到
Couldn't even do that.
你为什么要抽大烟
Why would you want to be smoking that for?
跟你一样的原因啊
Same reason as you.
脑袋疼
Pain in the head.
我跟莉兹谈过了
I spoke to Lizzie.
我把你告诉我的事更她说了
I told her what you told me.
她说  你哥哥汤米是个下流的骗子
She said, "Your brother Tommy is a dirty liar."
但之后我跟她妹妹和表亲们谈了谈
But then I spoke to her sister and her cousin.
给他们买了一些酒
Bought them a couple drinks.
他们说  她现在就接一些常客  仅此而已
"Just a few of regulars," They said. "That's all."
"为了不让饿狼来找麻烦
"To keep the wolf from the door,
她依然会接待一些常客
"She still sees a couple of regulars."
你一定认为我是个大傻瓜
You must think I'm an idiot.
我觉得你是谢尔比家族历史上第一个
I think you're the first Shelby in history...
在某方面有合法证件的人
to have a legal licence for anything.
我们的爷爷会怎么说呢
What would our granddad say, eh?
他会在坟墓里打滚
He'd be turning in his grave.
"老实工作赚来的钱"
"Honest bloody money? Eh?"
"在这个家里  就在这儿吗"
"In this house? Here?"
我们小时候  你总喜欢模仿别人的声音
You always used to do voices when we were kids.
我们现在不是小孩子了  约翰
We're not kids now, John.
但我们还是要相互照顾  对吗
But we still have to look out for each other, right?
是啊
Yeah.
来吧  回家去  睡个好觉
Come on. Go home. Get some sleep.
我们明天有大事要办
We've got a big day tomorrow.
有吗
We have?
明天  我们要永久性结束和李氏家族的战争
Tomorrow, we finish the war with the Lees for once and for all.
-什么时候变这样了  -就从现在开始
- Since when? - Since just now.
明天十点钟
Ten o'clock tomorrow.
准备好面对一切
Be ready for anything.
都下车吧  兄弟们
Out you get, boys.
准备好了吗  兄弟们
Ready, boys?
-约翰  准备好了吗  -是的  我没事
- John, ready? - Yeah. Yeah I'm fine.
来喝一口
Have a drink.
怎么了  干嘛都看着我  怎么了
What? What are you all staring at me for? What?
很好  我们出发吧
Good. Let's go.
怎么了
What?
汤米  你在搞什么呢
Tommy, what you playing at?
我们进入猎枪打击范围了
We're in shotgun range.
约翰
John...
在你开战前
Before you go into battle,
你需要一样东西
there's something you are going to need.
你他妈是在干什么呢  汤米
What are you bloody doing, Tommy?
笑一个  约翰  这是个婚礼
Smile, John, it's a wedding.
-谁的婚礼  -如果我们告诉你了
- Whose bloody wedding? - Now if we'd told you,
你就不会来了
you wouldn't have come.
李氏家族有个姑娘  她会有一点狂野
There's a girl from the Lee family who's going a bit wild.
-她需要你去娶她  -滚开
- And she needs marrying her off. - Fuck!
-约翰  -你没权利这么做  汤米
- John! - You have no bloody right, Tommy!
听我说  听我说
Listen to me. Listen to me.
一个需要丈夫的女人  一个需要妻子的男人
A girl who needs a husband. A man who needs a wife.
汤米  我他妈才不要娶一个捡蘑菇的姑娘
Tommy, I'm not bloody marrying some fucking mushroom picker!
嘘  小约翰  听着
Shh, John boy, come on. Listen.
我已经替你许过婚了
I have already betrothed you.
所以如果你现在退出
So if you back out now
这里马上就会爆发一场血腥的战争
there's going to be one fucking mighty war breaking out here
那会让索姆河战役
that's going to make the Somme...
那会让索姆河战役相比之下就跟茶话会一样
It's going to make the Somme look like a fucking tea party.
但如果你娶了她
But if you marry her,
我们家族和李氏家族将永远团结在一起
our family and the Lee family will be united for ever.
战争也会就此结束  一切取决于你  约翰
And this war will be over. It's up to you John.
战争
War...?
还是和平
..Or peace?
放开我
Let go of me.
对嘛  你该看看她的嫁妆有多豪华
Right... You should see the size of her dowry.
她的什么
Her what?
她爸要送你一辆车
Her dad is giving you a car.
他行吗
Will he do?
他可以
He'll do.
她来了
Here she is.
她最好别超过50岁
She'd better be under 50.
过来  上吧
Come here. Go on.
我们今天是来参加
We're here today to join in matrimony
这位先生和这位女士的婚礼
this man and this woman...
你看上去很不错
You look well.
祝他们生活和谐  永不分离
And harmony and togetherness.
他们的婚姻得到了我们身边
Which is sanctioned and honoured
两个大家族的赞许和支持
by the presence and the power of these two families around us.
约翰·迈克尔·谢尔比
Do you John Michael Shelby
你愿意娶伊丝米·玛莎·李为妻吗
take Esme Martha Lee to be your beautiful wife?
你收到我的邀请函了吗
You got my invitation?
格蕾丝说我们会休战
Grace said there's a truce.
家人团聚日
Family day.
你丈夫来不了吗
Your husband couldn't make it?
他不跟我说话了
He's not speaking to me.
当他开口的时候
And when he does
就会骂我是该死的谢尔比家族的人
he calls me a fucking Shelby
尽管我现在应该是索恩家族的人
even though I'm a Thorne now.
对我来说你就是索恩家的  那是肯定的
Thorn in my side, that's for sure.
相扶相持
To have and hold...
我的天啊  汤米
My God, Tommy.
你羡慕他  对吧
You admire him, don't you?
仪式还剩最后一项
There remains one more part of the ceremony.
就是双方血液的融合
It's the mingling of the two bloods.
就此  两个家族将结合为一个
Where the two families become the one...family.
我现在宣布你们结为夫妇
I now pronounce you man and wife!
快点  约翰  快亲吻新娘吧
Come on, John, kiss the bride will you?
*我整夜睡在一个锅匠的臂弯里*
*Oh, I slept all night in a tinker's arms*
*他的手臂环绕着我*
*He put his arms around me*
*人群相庆  舞蹈跳起*
*Oh, there was folks and there was dance*
*爱尔兰人丢了班卓琴*
*And Paddy here's lost his banjo*
*我不愿离开我的宝贝*
*I wouldn't part from my sweetheart*
*不管是2便士  1/2便士或1/4便士*
*Tuppence, ha'penny or farthing*
*又来一群驾马车的男人*
*Another load of wagon men*
快点  再把我转一圈
Come on, spin me round again.
你该让艾达小心一点
You should tell Ada to slow down.
你觉得她会听我的吗
You think she'll listen to me?
我试过阻止她  但她一直在喝酒
I tried to stop her but she's been drinking.
在那种狭小的地下室困了好几周
Been stuck in that little basement for weeks.
好不容易出来了还能怎样呢
What do we expect?
她就像爆竹炸开了一样
She's going off like a firecracker.
天啊  汤米  快去阻止吧
Oh, Christ, Tommy, please...
够了  快过来  够了
Enough now. Come on. Enough.
好了  快来  坐下
All right, Ada, come on, have a rest,
-坐下  -快看啊  伊丝米
- Sit down. - Come and look, Esme.
看看你加入了怎样的一个家族
Come and look at the family you've joined.
来看看掌控这个家族的男人
Come and look at the man who runs it.
为他的兄弟选择妻子
Chooses his brother's wives for them.
他把自己的妹妹当老鼠一样追捕
He hunts his own sister down like a rat
他还想杀了自己的妹夫
and he tries to kill his own brother-in-law!
艾达  够了
Ada, that's enough.
现在  他妈的都不肯让我跳支舞
And now he won't even let me have a fucking dance!
-在婚礼上都他妈不行  -让她坐下
- Not even at a fucking wedding! - Sit her down.
冷静  艾达  艾达  冷静
Calm down, Ada. Ada, calm down.
该死的
Holy shit!
快拿水来
Water. Right.
别现在啊  艾达  该死的  你真会挑时间
Not now, Ada. Bloody hell, you do pick your times!
你人生中最了不起的事  亚瑟
Story of your fucking life, Arthur.
好了  我们到了
Right, we are here.
下来吧
Come on.
车不错啊  约翰  跑起来怎么样
Nice car, John. How's she run?
很好  很顺畅
Yeah, beautiful. Really smooth.
你妹妹在里面生孩子
Your sister in there giving birth,
你却在外面谈论车
you're talking about the bloody car.
-我们男人也帮不上什么忙  波莉  -除了去喝酒
- Not much us men can do now, Pol. - Except go get drunk.
-对  走吧  -有个男人该待在这里
- Right, come on. - There's one man should be here.
你说的对  波莉  弗莱迪该在这里
You are right, Pol, Freddie should be here.
我是听见你胸膛里的心跳声了吗
Is that a heartbeat I hear inside that chest?
休战协议到天亮依然有效  我发誓
The truce lasts till sunrise. On my oath.
告诉弗莱迪来这里没事
Tell Freddie it's safe.
艾达
Ada!
好了兄弟们  我们去痛快喝一顿吧
Right, boys, let's wet this baby's head.
继续用力  就这样  用力
Keep going. That's right. Push.
我觉得婴儿好像倒错位置了
I think it might be the wrong way round.
我给三位姐妹接过生
I tended three sisters.
是啊  你说的对
Yeah, I think you're right.
-我们该让她向前趴着  -快点  艾达
- We should move her forward. - Come on, Ada.
来吧  快点
Right, come on.
就快了  亲爱的
It's not long to go now, darling.
用力  二  三
Push. Two, three.
两个美丽的女人
Two beautiful women.
我该走了  该走了  今天是我的洞房花烛夜
I should go. I should go. It's my wedding night.
不  你坐下
No, you sit down.
有孩子要出生时  你最好别出现在女人当中
You don't want to be among the women when there's a baby coming.
再来一杯
Have another.
你觉得她丈夫
So, do you think her husband
会接受同样的建议  躲得远远的吗
will take the same advice and stay away?
不  弗莱迪会去的  什么都阻止不了他
Nah. Freddie will be there. Nothing will keep him away.
汤米说他去那里不会有事的
Tommy's said it's all right for him to be there.
对吧  汤米
Isn't that right, Tommy?
对  我今晚心慈仁厚
That's right. I'm all heart tonight.
你知道吗  小约翰
You know what, John boy?
我觉得是那个可爱的酒吧招待女
I think it's that lovely barmaid,
刚刚走出去的那个可爱的酒吧招待女
that pretty barmaid that's just walked out
让我们的兄弟变得心慈手软了
that's made our brother go all soft.
为这个干一杯
Drinks to that.
艾达
Ada!
快点  快打开
Come on, open up.
好了  亲爱的
There you go, love.
他可真漂亮
Oh, he's beautiful.
是个儿子  弗莱迪
It's a boy, Freddie.
真是个漂亮的儿子
It's a beautiful baby boy.
真乖啊
There you go.
欢迎来到这个世界  儿子
Welcome to the world, Son.
欢迎
Welcome.
开门  警察
Open up! Police!
弗莱迪
Freddie?
你们不能进来  有个宝宝刚刚出生
You can't come in here, there's a baby just been born.
弗莱迪
Freddie?
别伤害他  弗莱迪
Don't hurt him. Freddie!
你们伤到他了  别碰他
You are hurting him, leave him alone.
你们要将我从儿子面前带走吗
You're taking me away from my baby?
-艾达  -弗莱迪
- Ada! - Freddie!
你现在想让我打开那瓶香槟吗
You want me to open that champagne now?
是个儿子
It's a boy.
波  波莉
Pol? Polly?
波莉  波莉
Polly! Polly!
但警察把他的父亲抓走了
But the police came and took his father away!
你敢这样看着我
Don't you DARE look at me like that!
你个骗子
You liar!